{
    "id": "7939712c0da04d98a84013b67a3f4da8",
    "title": "Conditional Sentences Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I knew what he was up to, I …………………………. him go.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not let",
                "would not let",
                "would not have let"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "47e8d913cafe40adbd07ebc9b7f5baab"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ………………………. more money, she could buy a home.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "earns",
                "earned",
                "had earned"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b333fda3e59d4d438c7a9e50855d9faa"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you eat more greens, your health …………………………….",
            "description": "In type 1 conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will improve",
                "would improve",
                "would have improved"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d5d69e86d6774c31a6f11b62a819c1b1"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had recognized you, she …………………………….. you.",
            "description": "In type 3 conditional, use a past perfect in the if-clause and would /could/might have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will greet",
                "would greet",
                "would have greeted"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "773f16847d4f4dbbb80ea06121b59d9f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………………….. her address, I could have contacted her.",
            "description": "In type 3 conditional, use a past perfect in the if-clause and would /could/might have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "didn't lose",
                "haven't lost",
                "hadn't lost"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a16986f2338b4ea28807914ddd784b97"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ……………………………… timely treatment, she would die.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "don't receive",
                "didn't receive",
                "hadn't received"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d0fb80e31052407d942f80c92a31bf6a"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………………. the cops, this crime could have been prevented.",
            "description": "In type 3 conditional, use a past perfect in the if-clause and would /could/might have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "alert",
                "alerted",
                "had alerted"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "186af49e4b9f4f98bdb2064bc145a81f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If he had invested his money, he …………………………….. rich now.",
            "description": "In type 3 conditional, use a past perfect in the if-clause and would /could/might have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will become",
                "would become",
                "would have become"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "65e09e70fe214064be8717e4bbd67532"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you don’t behave, I ………………………….. you out.",
            "description": "In type 1 conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will throw",
                "would throw",
                "would have thrown"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c7727fa1cdc04767b52e98aad632af6d"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had learned her lesson, she ……………………………… the same mistake.",
            "description": "In type 3 conditional, use a past perfect in the if-clause and would /could/might have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not commit",
                "would not commit",
                "would not have committed"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7005396525474274b456674a066167d8"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. right, you will be healthy.",
            "description": "In type 1 conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "eat",
                "ate",
                "had eaten"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "82dcfaef8cdd4e67928c7528bea255ff"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ………………………….. aloud, I would have heard her.",
            "description": "In type 3 conditional, use a past perfect in the if-clause and would /could/might have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "call",
                "called",
                "had called"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d97f865b78104258b239faa27dcd13fa"
        }
    ]
}